icebreaker.com 2019-02-23

# Privacy Policy

* * *

 Last Updated: 29 March 2018

This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes how personal information about you is collected, used and disclosed by Icebreaker Nature Clothing Inc and our subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, "Icebreaker") with respect to your use of our websites where this Policy is posted. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Icebreaker Nature Clothing Inc and other companies in its group, participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Icebreaker is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

Icebreaker is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Icebreaker is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>, or if you have questions or complaints regarding this Policy or Icebreaker's privacy practices, please contact us at:

ICEBREAKER NORTH AMERICA  
21 WATER STREET, SUITE 502  
VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA  
V6B 1A1  
1 877 827 6816  

We collect personal information about you in various ways, such as when you create an account or online profile, use the interactive areas and features on our websites, make a purchase, participate in our contests or surveys or when you email, call or otherwise communicate with us. Such information may include your name, address, email address, phone number, fax number, photographs, credit card information and other contact or demographic information you choose to provide. We may also obtain information about you from other sources and link or combine that with information we collect on our websites.

We collect your location based information for the purpose of locating a place that you may be searching for in your area. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service. You may opt-out of location based services at any time by emailing us at [customerservice.us@icebreaker.com](mailto:customerservice.us@icebreaker.com).

We also automatically collect information about you when you access or use our websites. For example, we automatically log your computer's operating system, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, access times, browser type and language and the website you visited before navigating to our websites. We may also collect information about your usage and activity on our websites. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you.

Our website also uses our authorized third-party analytics vendors, such as Google Analytics. Please click here for more information about how data is collected and processed in connection with the Google Analytics service: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve and understand the success of marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

We and our marketing partners use cookies or similar tracking technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. Among other things, cookies help us improve our websites and your experience. We use cookies to see which areas and features are popular and to count visits to our websites. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s "help" file. Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove and/or reject cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect certain features of our websites.

Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union [click here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

How We Use Your Information

We use the personal information we collect for the purposes described in this Policy or otherwise disclosed to you on our websites. For example, we may use your information to:

  * operate and improve our websites;
  * provide and deliver products and services, process and complete transactions and send you related information, including purchase confirmations, shipping alerts, invoices, updates, security alerts, recall notices and support and administrative messages;
  * maintain and administer your online account;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * send you news and information about events, activities, offers, promotions, products and services offered by Icebreaker or third parties that we think will be of interest to you;
  * create targeted audiences with third parties for advertising purposes;
  * process and deliver contest or sweepstakes entries and prizes; and
  * link or combine with other personal information we receive from third parties to help understand your needs and provide you with better service.

We may store and process personal information in the United States and in other countries.

Disclosure of Information Policy

It is our policy not to share personal information collected through our websites with third parties except as described in this Policy or as otherwise disclosed to you on our websites. For example, we may share personal information as follows:

  * when you give us your consent to do so, including if we notify you on our websites that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information;
  * when you provide a product review or you post content to interactive areas or features of our websites;
  * with third party vendors, consultants and service providers that perform services to help us with our business activities (such as shipping your order, offering customer service or targeted advertising) and who need access to such information to carry out their work for us. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us
  * when we believe in good faith that we are lawfully authorized or required to do so or that doing so is reasonably necessary or appropriate to comply with the law or to respond to lawful requests, legal process or legal authorities;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, respond to an emergency or investigate fraud; and
  * in connection with, or during negotiations of, a merger, acquisition, financing or sale of all or a portion of Icebreaker's assets.

We may also share aggregated information that does not directly identify you.

Send Your Wish List to a Friend

If you choose to use our website to send your wish list to a friend, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site to review your wish list. Icebreaker does not store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

Links to Other Web Sites

Our websites include links to other websites. This Policy does not apply to linked sites and we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices of those sites. Any personal information you provide to a linked site is provided directly to a third party and is subject to such third party's privacy policy. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policies of any website you visit before providing any personal information.

Security

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [privacy@icebreaker.com](mailto:privacy@icebreaker.com).

Your Information Choices and Changes

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or emailing us at [customerservice.us@icebreaker.com](mailto:customerservice.us@icebreaker.com). If you opt out of receiving such communications, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your account, purchases or our ongoing business relations.

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or delete or ask to have it removed from our blog by making the change on our member information page, emailing our Customer Support at [customerservice.us@icebreaker.com](mailto:customerservice.us@icebreaker.com) or contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within 30 days or within a reasonable timeframe.

Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [customerservice.us@icebreaker.com](mailto:customerservice.us@icebreaker.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Twitter button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Frames

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to/from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our website. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to [www.icebreaker.com](https://www.icebreaker.com/).

User Generated Content

When you transmit, upload, post, email or otherwise make available data, text, software, music, sounds, photographs, images, graphics, designs, artwork, messages or other materials created or sourced by you ("User Content") to Icebreaker and/or on icebreaker.com or any other website, internet site or application (including mobile device applications) that is owned, operated, controlled or sponsored by Icebreaker, you agree and acknowledge the following:

Suitable content

The User Content must not violate any law, contain any commercial messages, or comparisons or solicitations for products or services, be offensive, defamatory, sexually explicit, violent, vulgar, derogatory of any ethnicity , race, gender, religion, profession or age group, promote any political agenda, promote alcohol, drugs, tobacco, firearms/weapons, promote, include or refer to activities that may be harmful or illegal, and/or any other content that is considered inappropriate or unsuitable as determined by Icebreaker at its sole discretion.

No Intellectual property rights infringement

You warrant that the User Content is your original work and/or that you own the intellectual property rights in the User Content, and that the User Content does not infringe on any copyright, trade mark or other intellectual property rights of any other person or organization. You waive your moral rights in relation to the User Content and you will not assert such rights against Icebreaker, its sub-licensees or assigns.

You waive your moral rights in relation to the User Content and you will not assert such rights against Icebreaker, its sublicensees or assigns.

No privacy rights infringement

If the User Content incorporates personal information, including the identity or image of any individual, you confirm that the individual concerned has consented to the use of the image and personal information.

Removal of User Content

Icebreaker may, with or without any notice to you, at its sole discretion and for any reason, remove, modify or block access to any User Content.

Licence granted to Icebreaker

You grant Icebreaker a non-exclusive, perpetual, worldwide, irrevocable, royalty free, transferrable and sub-licensable right to use, modify, edit and display the User Content, including copyright in the User Content, in any media known now or in the future.

No liability for User Content

Icebreaker makes no representations or warranties as the accuracy, reliability, lawfulness or completeness of any User Content, and takes no responsibility for the use of or reliance on, any User Content by you or any third party.

Notification of Privacy Policy Changes

We may update this Policy at any time to reflect changes to our information practices and we will indicate when changes have been made by revising the date at the top of the Policy. If we make any material changes to this Policy, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by posting a prominent notice on our websites prior to the date such changes become effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Us

If you have a question about this Policy, please contact us at:

icebreaker.com  
21 WATER STREET, SUITE 502  
VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA  
V6B 1A1
